CASTRO GONZÁLEZ, JOSÉ ANGEL

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Computer systems engineer with significant experience in Java, Go, and Python. I have successfully developed and maintained complex systems, recently focusing on telematics projects and web applications. Currently, I am designing involved in prototyping a production planning web application using Figma. I am a proactive team player with a continuous improvement mindset, always leveraging my skills to tackle new challenges and drive project success.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Programming in Python (coursera)
- Back-End Development (coursera)
- Basic programming in Go (platzi)

INTERESTS

Apart from being a software developer, I like to take courses online, enjoy playing soccer and being with my family, also I play videogames, and spend a large amount of my free time exploring the latest technology advancements.

SOFT SKILLS

- · Committed
- · Time Management
- Teamwork
- Communication
- · Proactive
- Detail Oriented
- Analytic
- Continuous Improvement Mindset

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Go
- Java
- Javascript
- Terraform

CONTACT DETAILS

Mobile: 33 11 45 04 88 angel.c.g.027@gmail.com 45066, Zapopan, Jalisco

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native) English (Intermediate – B1) https://github.com/NaYpE

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Continental | Apr 2022 - Aug 2024

Proiects:

• Key as a Service (Apr 2022 - Apr 2023)

I worked on the development, maintenance, and testing of the Key as a Service product. I successfully developed and integrated new features, ensuring user requirements were met effectively. I enhanced existing APIs, resolved various issues, and ensured the continuous improvement of the application. I documented improvements and provided technical and usage details to internal and external stakeholders.

• Zonar (May 2023 – Aug 2023)

Developed and maintained telematics-related features similar to KaaS, gained expertise in laaS with Terraform, and was involved in the migration from clearblade IoT Core to google IoT Core.

• Live Maps (Sep 2023 - Abr 2024)

Worked on backend tasks and contributed to continuous improvements and application support for this project related to Zonar (telematics) focused on the European Union. Assisted in the migration of the infrastructure from NA to EU.

• Production Planner (May 2024 - Aug 2024)

Participated in the creation of a new tool designed to help the production line easily create production plans. This tool will effectively manage the production process and significantly optimize production by minimizing the creation of surpluses.

Technology used:

• Go • Angular

Jenkins

Postman • GCP

Terraform

Java

Docker

MongoDB

Kubernetes

GCPPythonDataDog

TCS - TATA Consultancy Services | May 2021 - Apr 2022 Project:

• DOW

I worked on the Design, Development and maintenance of frontend web pages, creating user interfaces and implementing navigation logic and database access.

Technology used:

• Power Apps • HTML 5

• CMS • CSS3

• .NET • JavaScript

HCL Technologies | Jul 2019 - May 2021

Project:

USAA

Developed, maintained, and tested applications for internal clients and REST APIs. Created new features, fixed bugs, and implemented unit and functional tests.

Technology used:

JavaJest

React
JUnit5

Springboot

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO JOSÉ MARIO MOLINA PASQUEL Y ENRÍQUEZ

Computer System Engineer (2019)